Juan Sebastian Caicedo Alfonso

Software developer | Electronic engineer | 🐞 www.jseb.dev

Experience

Backend Developer - at MobSoftGames

Jan 2023 - Present

Revolutionizing the way to deliver AI models to cloud instances through continuous delivery strategies implemented utilizing AWS services. Orchestrating the storage of company and client data, integrating S3 buckets into the company's workflow leading to faster and more accurate insights. Creating and terminating dedicated instances in the cloud using secure SSH connections, maximizing security, and minimizing the time for dedicated instances to be ready to use to train or use AI models. Technology Stack: Python, PyTorch, S3 bucket, AWS Lambda, SSH.

FullStack Developer - at Encora

Apr 2022 - Oct 2022

Migrate cutting-edge technology tool recently acquired by the company for intelligent process development in the biopharmaceutical and biotech industry. Learned and migrated legacy technology from a heavy code load of more than 30 repositories to the client system before their first release. Investigate and find the root causes of several bugs in the repositories that prevented the seamless flow of data between the database, the cache, and the front end. Technology stack: **React, Python, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Gitlab CICD, AWS, SQS, Lambda**.

Software Developer - at Nufi

May 2021 - Apr 2022

Develop proof of concepts and new products for the company. Developed Whatsapp chatbots that retrieve info from public ids through OCR and deliver full reports of the id owner. Designed RESTFUL APIs for new services to offer to clients, implementing them in the company's servers, and creating a graphical feature in the website to display and use these news services. Develop apps that implement third-party APIs to obtain and store clients' data. Overall, my contribution expanded the communication channels between the company and its end users. Technology stack: React, React native, node.js, express, selenium, Stripe, Twilio, Python, Django, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, AWS RDS.

Coding Teacher - old teacher profile

May 2016 - May 2021

Autonomous virtual teacher to students worldwide. Main topics: Javascript, Python, React, Java, linear algebra, differential calculus.

Projects

MaiMovies - article video

Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

Developed with **React Native** and **Mobx** for **Android** and **IOS** a mobile app to create and edit personal lists of audiovisual media.

Booking Experience - deployment video

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

Design, develop and deploy a website for clients of a booking company. Features in the first version: Creating new booking locations, creating, editing, and deleting bookings, changing theme according to machine preference supporting Android, IOS, and Windows. Build with **NextJs, ReactJs, and Redux**

Port-ecommerce.shop - <u>deployment</u>

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

Design, develop and deploy a massive E-commerce website store. This full-stack project, is built with **Nextjs, React, Redux, Django, Graphql, docker, and Postgres**. It's fully deployed and implements features like creating accounts, authentication with JWT, image uploading and storing, profile editing, email password reset, and tag and search engine.

Know your business - Web App

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021

Develop a web application that uses Nufi's APIs to retrieve information from any company. Technology Stack **Django, and React** as back-end and front-end frameworks.

Cryptographic system based on AES-256 (TESIS)

Jun 2015 - May 2016

Design and develop a secure and efficient implementation of the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) algorithm with a key size of 256 bits. This project provides a **Python** implementation of AES-256 encryption and decryption using the **PyCrypto** library.

Details

github.com/jsebdev

in linkedin.com/in/jsebdev

✓ jsebdev@gmail.com

9 +57 317 858 4597

Technical Skills

Cloud and Backend

- Python
- AWS
- Node.js
- Django
- SQL
- NoSQL
- Docker
- Graphql
- CICD

Frontend

- Javascript
- TypeScript
- React
- React Native
- Nextis
- MobX
- Redux

Profile

Software developer with a keen sense of order and optimization. Thanks to my eagerness to learn and research I've developed different solutions for the fintech, and pharmaceutical industries. Developed integration of automated API messaging services, design architecture, web scraping, data manipulation, and serverless computing in AWS.

Languages

• Spanish: Native

• English: Conversational

Proficient

• French: Basic A2

Education

Full stack software developer, Holberton School

Feb 2021 - Jan 2022

Holberton School is a peer-learning, project-guided, and self-learning-based full-stack software engineering school. At Holberton, I could propose and lead 5 different projects from the usual curriculum. Build several full-stack projects in teams of 5 with a basis in **Python**, **Javascript Django**, **SQL**, **NoSQL**, **REST**, **GraphQL**, **React**, **Webpack**, **and Babel**.

Electronic Engineer, Universidad del Valle

2011 - 2016

Electronic engineering bachelor. Learned to design, develop and implement software programs to meet the needs of cutting-edge electronic devices and systems.

Courses & Certifications

- Kotlin Course 2023
- Django Course: Testing, Static Files, Django Admin - 2022
- Django Course 2022
- Professional Python Development Course -2022
- AWS Cloud Computing Compute, Storage and Databases - 2022
- AWS Cloud Computing with EC2 2022
- AWS Cloud Computing roles and security with IAM - 2022
- Introduction to AWS Cloud Computing -2022
- React Native Course 2022
- NextJs Course 2022
- Angular Course 2022
- React Course 2022
- Svelte Course 2022